ILR School Audio-Visual Department Films /4191 F
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILR School Audio-Visual Department Films
0000-2999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations (NYSSILR)
/4191 F
19.78 cubic feet
19.8 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
7897488
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 04, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 04, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4191 AV: ILR School Audio-Visual Department Video Cassette Collection
New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Audio-Visual Department
7897488
- Button, Button - item #1272 (Box 1)
  - Button, Button (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    item #1272
- Business of America - item #50 (Box 2)
  - Business of America (Box 2, Folder 1)
    item #50
- Bob Knowlton Story - item #1204 (Box 3)
  - Bob Knowlton Story (Box 3, Folder 1)
    item #1204
- Can't Take No More - item #95 (Box 4)
  - Can't Take No More (Box 4, Folder 1)
    item #95
- The Case of Barbara Parsons/reel 2 - item #7 (Box 5)
  - The Case of Barbara Parsons - reel 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    item #7
- Case of the Lost Fringe Benefit - item #1250 (Box 6)
  - Case of the Lost Fringe Benefit (Box 6, Folder 1)
    item #1250
- Case of Insubordination - item #1001 (Box 7)
  - Case of Insubordination (Box 7, Folder 1)
    item #1001
- Coaching ILR - no item # (Box 8)
  - Coaching ILR (Box 8, Folder 1)
    no item #
- A Continuing Responsibility - item #1522 (Box 9)
  - A Continuing Responsibility (Box 9, Folder 1)
    item #1522
- Controlling Interest - item #66 (Box 10)
  - Controlling Interest (Box 10, Folder 1)
    item #66
- Collective Bargaining Process - item #907 (Box 11)
  - Collective Bargaining Process (Box 11, Folder 1)
    item #907
- Challenge of Leadership (2) - item #901 (2) (Box 12)
  - Challenge of Leadership (2) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    item #901 (2)
- A Case of Working Smarter, Not Harder - item #56 (Box 13)
  - A Case of Working Smarter, Not harder (Box 13, Folder 1)
    item #56
- Day in the Night of Jonathan Mole - item #1206 (Box 14)
  - Day in the Night of Jonathan Mole (Box 14, Folder 1)
    item #1206
- Countdown to a Contract - item #1245 (Box 15)
  - Countdown to a Contract (Box 15, Folder 1)
    item #1245
- Contracting Out - item #1005 (Box 16)
  - Contracting Out (Box 16, Folder 1)
    item #1005
- Cornell - item #88 (Box 17)
  - Cornell (Box 17, Folder 1)
    item #88
- Controlling Interest - item #82 (Box 18)
  - Controlling Interest (Box 18, Folder 1)
    item #82
- Artists at Work - item #27 (Box 19)
  - Artists at Work (Box 19, Folder 1)
    item #27
- Assessing Management Potential - item #1255 (Box 20)
  - Assessing Management Potential (Box 20, Folder 1)
    item #1255
- Automation Next Revolution - item #103 (Box 21)
  - Automation Next Revolution (Box 21, Folder 1)
    item #103
- Are You Listening - item #906 (Box 22)
  - Are You Listening (Box 22, Folder 1)
    item #906
- Arbitration the Truth of the Matter II - item #1523 (Box 23)
  - Arbitration the Truth of the Matter II (Box 23, Folder 1)
    item #1523
- Arbitration by Adolph M. Koven - item #605 (Box 24)
  - Arbitration by Adolph M. Koven (Box 24, Folder 1)
    item #605
- Arbitration the Test of Justice - no item # (Box 25)
  - Arbitration the Test of Justice (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Behavior Modeling - item #56 (Box 26)
  - Behavior Modeling (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Balance Sheet Barrier - item #49 (Box 27)
  - Balance Sheet Barrier (Box 27, Folder 1)
    item #49
- Blue Collar Capitalism - no item # (Box 28)
  - Blue Collar Capitalism (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Blue Collar Trap, Part II - item #1267 (Box 29)
- Blue Collar Trap, Part I - item #1267 (Box 29)
  - Blue collar Trap, part I (Box 29, Folder 1)
    item #1267
- "Incredible Machine" - no item # (Box 30)
  - Incredible Machine (Box 30, Folder 1)
- "An Inside Look at Collective Bargaining" - no item # (Box 31)
  - An Inside Look at Collective Bargaining (Box 31, Folder 1)
- "The Indispensable Miss Spencer" no item # (Box 32)
  - The Indispensable Miss Spencer (Box 32, Folder 1)
- "The Impasse" - item #1042 (Box 33)
  - The Impasse (Box 33, Folder 1)
    item #1042
- "Japan" - item #36 (Box 34)
  - Japan (Box 34, Folder 1)
    item #36
- "Instruction or Obstruction" - item #903 (Box 35)
  - Instruction or Obstruction (Box 35, Folder 1)
    item #903
- "Joshua and the Blob" - no item # (Box 36)
  - Joshua and the Blob (Box 36, Folder 1)
- "Is it Always Right to be Right" -item #709 (1) (Box 37)
  - Is it Always Right to be Right? (Box 37, Folder 1)
    item #709 (1)
- "Is it Always Right to be Right?" - item #709 (2) (Box 38)
  - Is It Always Right to be Right? (Box 38, Folder 1)
    item #709 (2)
- The Case of Barbara Parsons/reel 2 - item #8 (Box 39)
  - The Case of Barbara Parsons - reel 2 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    item #8
- Case of the Lost Fringe Benefit - item #1250 (Box 40)
  - Case of the Lost Fringe Benefit (Box 40, Folder 1)
- "How Good is a Guy" - item #1015 (2) (Box 41)
  - How Good is a Guy (Box 41, Folder 1)
    item #1015 (2)
- "Helping: A Growing Dimension of Management" - item #2 (Box 42)
  - Helping: A Growing Dimension of Management (Box 42, Folder 1)
- "How Good is a Guy" - item #1015 (3) (Box 43)
  - How Good is a Guy (Box 43, Folder 1)
    item #1015 (3)
- "How Good is a Guy" - item #1015 (1) (Box 44)
  - How Good is a Guy (Box 44, Folder 1)
    item #1015 (1)
- "Judging People" - item #1020 (Box 45)
  - Judging People (Box 45, Folder 1)
    item #1020
- "Joshua in a Box" - no item # (Box 46)
  - Joshua and the Shadow (Box 46, Folder 1)
- "Joshua and the Shadow" - no item # (Box 47)
  - Joshua and the Shadow (Box 47, Folder 1)
- "Labor Law" - no item # (Box 48)
  - Labor Law (Box 48, Folder 1)
- "Learning & Behaving" - item #1219 (Box 49)
  - Learning & Behaving (Box 49, Folder 1)
    item #1219
- "If You Don't Come in Sunday" Part I & II - item #84 (Box 50)
  - If You Don't Come in Sunday, part I & II (Box 50, Folder 1)
    item #84
- "If You Don't Come in Sunday" Part I - item #1524 (Box 51)
  - If You Don't Come in Sunday Part I (Box 51, Folder 1)
    item #1524
- "If You Don't Come in Sunday" Part II -item #1524 (Box 52)
  - If You Don't come in Sunday, Part II (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Work Redesign - item #42 (Box 53)
  - Work Redesign (Box 53, Folder 1)
    item #42
- Management by Participation - item #1258 (Box 54)
  - Management by Participation (Box 54, Folder 1)
    item #1258
- Managerial Grid - item #1223 (Box 55)
  - Managerial Grid (Box 55, Folder 1)
    item #1223
- Managerial Grid (2) - item # 1223 (2) (Box 56)
  - Managerial Grid (2) (Box 56, Folder 1)
    item #1223 (2)
- "Listen Please" - no item # (Box 57)
  - Listen Please (Box 57, Folder 1)
- "Loose Bolts" - item #1269 (Box 58)
  - Loose Bolts (Box 58, Folder 1)
    item #1269
- "Like a Beautiful Child" - item #1221 (Box 59)
  - Like a Beautiful Child (Box 59, Folder 1)
    item #1221
- "Let's Arbitrate- Seniority v. Ability" - item #1220 (Box 60)
  - Let's Arbitrate - Seniority v. Ability (Box 60, Folder 1)
    item #1220
- "Let's Arbitrate: Seniority vs. Ability " - item #1220 (3) (Box 61)
  - Let's Arbitrate: Seniority vs. Ability (Box 61, Folder 1)
    item #1220 (3)
- "Like a Beautiful Child" - item #81 (Box 62)
  - Like a Beautiful Child (Box 62, Folder 1)
    item #81
- "Intrepreneurs" - item #909 A (Box 63)
  - Entrepreneurs (Box 63, Folder 1)
    item #909A
- "Intrepreneurs" - item #909 B (Box 64)
  - Entrepreneurs (Box 64, Folder 1)
    item 909 B
- "Havest of Shame" (2) - item #1507 (2) (Box 65)
  - Harvest of Shame (2) (Box 65, Folder 1)
    item #1507 (2)
- "Hard Bargaining" - item #1217 (Box 66)
  - Hard Bargaining (Box 66, Folder 1)
    item #1217
- "A Good Beginning" - item #902 (Box 67)
  - A Good Beginning (Box 67, Folder 1)
    item #902
- "Grievance Hearing" - item #1012 (Box 68)
  - Grievance Hearing (Box 68, Folder 1)
    item #1012
- "Group Think" / "Group Dynamics" - item #54 (Box 69)
  - Group Think / Group Dynamics (Box 69, Folder 1)
    item #54
- "Alternative to Discharge" - item #1037 (Box 70)
  - Alternative to Discharge (Box 70, Folder 1)
    item #1037
- "The American Woman: Portraits of Courage", Part 1 - item #1277, Pt I (Box 71)
  - The American Woman: Portraits of Courage", Part 1 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    item #1277, part I
- "All Things Considered: The Case of" - no item # (Box 72)
  - All Things Considered: The Case of (Box 72, Folder 1)
- The American Woman: Portraits of Courage, Part 2 - item #1277, Pt. II (Box 73)
  - The American Woman: Portraits of Courage, Part 2 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    item #1277, Pt. II
- "Arbitration in Action" - item #1501 (Box 74)
  - Arbitration in Action (Box 74, Folder 1)
    item #1501
- "Arbitration in Action" - item #1501 (Box 75)
  - Arbitration in Action (Box 75, Folder 1)
- "Different by Design" - no item # (Box 76)
  - Different by Design (Box 76, Folder 1)
- "Doctor, Lawyer, Merchant, Chief" - item #1038 (Box 77)
  - Doctor, Lawyer, Merchant, Chief (Box 77, Folder 1)
    item #1038
- "Decision at Delano" - item #1208 (Box 78)
  - Decision at Delano (Box 78, Folder 1)
    item #1208
- "Department Manager" - item #1209 (Box 79)
  - Department Manager (Box 79, Folder 1)
    item #1209
- "Delegating ILR" - no item # (Box 80)
  - Delegating ILR (Box 80, Folder 1)
- "Effective Decisions" - item #1251 (Box 81)
  - Effective Decisions (Box 81, Folder 1)
    item #1251
- "Don't Just Sit There" - no item # (Box 82)
  - Don't Just Sit there (Box 82, Folder 1)
- "Do Not Fold Spindle or Mutilate", pt. 1 - item #1505 (Box 83)
  - Do Not Fold Spindle or Mutilate, pt. 1 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    item #1505
- "Do Not Fold Spindle or Mutilate" - item #1505 (Box 84)
  - Do Not Fold Spindle or Mutilate (Box 84, Folder 1)
- "Drug Screening on the Job" - no item # (Box 85)
  - Drug Screening on the Job (Box 85, Folder 1)
- "The Effective Uses of Power & Authority" - item #117 (Box 86)
  - The Effective Uses of Power & Authority (Box 86, Folder 1)
    item #117
- "Focus on Tomorrow" - item #1253 (Box 87)
  - Focus on Tomorrow (Box 87, Folder 1)
    item #1253
- "Experimental Studies" - item #24 (Box 88)
  - Experimental Studies (Box 88, Folder 1)
    item #24
- "Eye of the Beholder" - item #1211 (1) (Box 89)
  - Eye of the Beholder (Box 89, Folder 1)
    item #1211 (1)
- "Global Assembly Line" - item #1500 (Box 90)
  - Global Assembly Line (Box 90, Folder 1)
    item #1500
- "A Matter of Survival" - item #1265 (Box 91)
  - A Matter of Survival (Box 91, Folder 1)
    item #1265
- "A Measure of Understanding" - item #1248 (Box 92)
  - A Measure of Understanding (Box 92, Folder 1)
    item #1248
- "Man Hunt" -item #46 (Box 93)
  - Man Hunt (Box 93, Folder 1)
    item #46
- "Managing Time" - item #1252 (Box 94)
  - Managing Time (Box 94, Folder 1)
    item #1252
- "Making Human Resources Productive" - item #1257 (Box 95)
  - Making Human Resources Productive (Box 95, Folder 1)
    item #1257
- "Managing Stress" - item #57 (Box 96)
  - Managing Stress (Box 96, Folder 1)
    item #57
- "Mediation in Action" (2) - item #1510 (2) (Box 97)
  - Mediation in Action (2) (Box 97, Folder 1)
    item #1510 (2)
- "Meetings, Bloody Meetings" - item #213 (Box 98)
  - Meetings, Bloody Meetings (Box 98, Folder 1)
    item #213
- "Mediation: Beginning of Conflict" - item #1203 (Box 99)
  - Mediation: Beginning of Conflict (Box 99, Folder 1)
    item #1203
- "Mediation in Action" - item #1510 (3) (Box 100)
  - Mediation in Action (Box 100, Folder 1)
    item #1510 (3)
- "Mediation: The Settlement" - item #1231 (Box 101)
  - Mediation: The Settlement (Box 101, Folder 1)
    item #1231
- "More than Words" - item # 904 (1) (Box 102)
  - More Than Words (Box 102, Folder 1)
    item #904 (1)
- "More than Words" - item #904 (2) (Box 103)
  - More Than Words (2) (Box 103, Folder 1)
    item #904 (2)
- "Mondragon" - item # 10 (Box 104)
  - Mondragon (Box 104, Folder 1)
    item #10
- "Monday Morning Absentee" item #1034 (Box 105)
  - Monday Morning Absentee (Box 105, Folder 1)
    item #1034
- "Motivation Classic" - no item # (Box 106)
  - Motivation Classic (Box 106, Folder 1)
- "New Truck Dilemma" - item #1226 (1) (Box 107)
  - New Truck Dilemma (Box 107, Folder 1)
    item #1226
- "Motivation Through Job Enrichment" - no item # (Box 108)
  - Motivation Through Job Enrichment (Box 108, Folder 1)
- "A New Look at Motivation" - item #51 (Box 109)
  - A New Look at Motivation (Box 109, Folder 1)
    item #51
- "New Truck Dilemma" - item #1226 (3) (Box 110)
  - New Truck Dilemma (Box 110, Folder 1)
    item #1226 (3)
- "Parliamentary Procedures in Action" - item #1027 (Box 111)
  - Parliamentary Procedures in Action (Box 111, Folder 1)
    item #1027
- "Organizing Begins at Home" item #45 (Box 112)
  - Organizing Begins at Home (Box 112, Folder 1)
    item #45
- "Nuts & Bolts of Performance Appraisal" - item #1271 (Box 113)
  - Nuts & Bolts of Performance Appraisal (Box 113, Folder 1)
    item #1271
- "Packingtown USA" - item #1227 (Box 114)
  - Packingtown USA (Box 114, Folder 1)
    item #1227
- "Occupational Safety & Health Ad" - no item # (Box 115)
  - Occupational Safety & Health Ad (Box 115, Folder 1)
- A Public Service Announcement from Cornell University - no item # (Box 116)
  - A Public Service Announcement from Cornell University (Box 116, Folder 1)
- "People at Work: A Right to Refuse?" - item #55 (Box 117)
  - People at Work: A Right to Refuse? (Box 117, Folder 1)
    item #55
- "Pattern for Instruction" - no item # (Box 118)
  - Pattern for Instruction (Box 118, Folder 1)
- "Perception" - no item # (Box 119)
  - Perception (Box 119, Folder 1)
- "Pay for Performance" - item #1259 (Box 120)
  - Pay for Performance (Box 120, Folder 1)
    item #1259
- Pattern for Instruction (2) - item # 1021 (2) (Box 121)
  - Pattern for Instruction (2) (Box 121, Folder 1)
    item #1021 (2)
- "A Power Pinch" - item #44 (Box 122)
  - A Power Pinch (Box 122, Folder 1)
    item #44
- "A Piece of Cake" - item #1513 - I (Box 123)
  - A Piece of Cake (Box 123, Folder 1)
    item #1513 - I
- "A Piece of Cake" - item #1513 - II (Box 124)
  - A Piece of Cake (Box 124, Folder 1)
    item #1513 - II
- "Performance Appraisal: The Human Dynamics" - item #3 (Box 125)
  - Performance Appraisal: The Human Dynamics (Box 125, Folder 1)
    item #3
- "A Perfectly Normal Day" - no item # (Box 126)
  - A Perfectly Normal Day (Box 126, Folder 1)
- "This Matter of Motivation: The Puzzle" - item #726 (Box 127)
  - This Matter of Motivation: The Puzzle (Box 127, Folder 1)
    item #726
- "Preventing Sexual Harrassment" - no item # (Box 128)
  - Preventing Sexual Harassment (Box 128, Folder 1)
- "Prodcution 5118 (3) - item #1228 (3) (Box 129)
  - Production 5118 (3) (Box 129, Folder 1)
    item #1228 (3)
- "Rosie the Riveter" - item #30 (Box 130)
  - Rosie the Riveter (Box 130, Folder 1)
    item #30
- The State of the Unions - item #1514 (Box 131)
  - The State of the Unions (Box 131, Folder 1)
    item #1514
- Shop Steward - item #1022 (Box 132)
  - Shop Steward (Box 132, Folder 1)
    item #1022
- School of Industrial and Labor Relations - item #1035 (Box 133)
  - School of Industrial and Labor Relations (Box 133, Folder 1)
    item #1035
- The Search: M.I.T. on Automation - item #1230 (Box 134)
  - The Search: M.I.T. on automation (Box 134, Folder 1)
    item #1230
- Song of the Canary, Part II - no item # (Box 135)
  - Song of the Canary, Part II (Box 135, Folder 1)
- Song of the Canary, Part I - no item # (Box 136)
  - Song of the Canary, Part I (Box 136, Folder 1)
- Senority vs. Ability - item #1526 (Box 137)
  - Senority vs. Ability (Box 137, Folder 1)
    item #1526
- Taybr Chain II - no item # (Box 138)
  - Taybr Chain II (Box 138, Folder 1)
- Strength of Leaders - item #1515 (Box 139)
  - Strength of Leaders (Box 139, Folder 1)
    item #1515
- Supervision - no item # (Box 140)
  - Supervision (Box 140, Folder 1)
- Styles of Leadership - item #1235 (Box 141)
  - Styles of Leadership (Box 141, Folder 1)
    item #1235
- "A Three Pipe Problem" - item #1270 (Box 142)
  - A Three Pipe Problem (Box 142, Folder 1)
    item #1270
- "Tell Me About Yourself" - no item # (Box 143)
  - Tell Me About Yourself (Box 143, Folder 1)
- "Story of the NLRB" - item #1023 (Box 144)
  - Story of the NLRB (Box 144, Folder 1)
    item #1023
- "Team Building" - item #1260 (Box 145)
  - Team Building (Box 145, Folder 1)
    item #1260
- "Time of Your Life" - no item # (Box 146)
  - Time of Your Life (Box 146, Folder 1)
- "Trouble With Archie" - no item # (Box 147)
  - Trouble With Archie (Box 147, Folder 1)
- "Understanding Motivation" - item #1238 (Box 148)
  - Understanding Motivation (Box 148, Folder 1)
    item #1238
- "Union Maids" - no item # (Box 149)
  - Union Maids (Box 149, Folder 1)
- "Union at Work" - item #38 -- Spanish version (Box 150)
  - Union at Work (Box 150, Folder 1)
    item #38 -- Spanish version
- "Trouble in the Firehouse" - item #1266 (Box 151)
  - Trouble in the Firehouse (Box 151, Folder 1)
    item #1266
- "The Trolley- By Golly" - item #1032 (Box 152)
  - The Trolley- By Golly (Box 152, Folder 1)
    item #1032
- "Union Maids, #2" - item #29B (Box 153)
  - Union Maids, #2 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    item #29B
- "Meeting in Progress" - item # 1511 (2) (Box 154)
  - Meeting in Progress (Box 154, Folder 1)
    item #1511 (2)
- "Meeting in Progress" - item #1511 (1) (Box 155)
  - Meeting in Progress (Box 155, Folder 1)
    item #1511 (1)
- "Miles of Smiles, Years of Struggle, pt. I" - item #31 (Box 156)
  - Miles of Smiles, years of Struggle, pt. 1 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    item #31
- "Miles of Smiles, Years of Struggle, pt. 2" - item #31 (Box 157)
  - Miles of Smiles, Years of Struggle, pt. 2 (Box 157, Folder 1)
- "With Babies and Banners" - item #39 (Box 158)
  - With Babies and Banners (Box 158, Folder 1)
    item #39
- "With Babies and Banners" - no item # (Box 159)
  - With Babies and Banners (Box 159, Folder 1)
- "Who Wants to Play God?" - no item # (Box 160)
  - Who Wants to Play God? (Box 160, Folder 1)
- "Who Wants Unions?" - item #48 (Box 161)
  - Who Wants unions? (Box 161, Folder 1)
    item #48
- "Why Man Creates" - item # 1241 (2) (Box 162)
  - Why Man Creates (Box 162, Folder 1)
    item #1241 (2)
- "Why Not a Woman?" - item #102 (Box 163)
  - Why Not a Woman? (Box 163, Folder 1)
    item #102
- "Worker to Worker" - no item # (Box 164)
  - Worker to Worker (Box 164, Folder 1)
- "Workplace Hustle" - no item # (Box 165)
  - Workplace Hustle (Box 165, Folder 1)
- "The Union Cause" -item #94 (Box 166)
  - The Union cause (Box 166, Folder 1)
    item #94
- "Voices from a Steel Town" -item #1014 (Box 167)
  - Voices from a Steel Town (Box 167, Folder 1)
    item #1014
- "The Vine and the Fig Tree" - item #1240 (Box 168)
  - The Vine and the Fig Tree (Box 168, Folder 1)
    item #1240
- "Unions Today: New Tactics to Tackle" - item #72 (Box 169)
  - Unions Today: New Tactics to Tackle (Box 169, Folder 1)
    item #72
- "Welcome Aboard" - item #1030 (Box 170)
  - Welcome Aboard (Box 170, Folder 1)
    item #1030
- "What Could You Do With A Nickel"? - no item # (Box 171)
  - What Could You Do With a Nickel? (Box 171, Folder 1)
- "What Can I Contribute?" - item #1261 (Box 172)
  - What Can I Contribute? (Box 172, Folder 1)
    item #1261
- "You" - item #908 (Box 173)
  - You (Box 173, Folder 1)
    item #908
- "You're Coming Along Fine" - item #1029 (Box 174)
  - You're Coming Along Fine (Box 174, Folder 1)
    item #1029
- "You Are There at the Bargaining Table" - item #1521 (1) (Box 175)
  - You Are There at the Bargaining Table (Box 175, Folder 1)
    item #1521
- "You Are There at the Bargaining Table" - item #1521 (2) (Box 176)
  - You Are There at the Bargaining Table (Box 176, Folder 1)
- You'll Soon Get the Hang Of It - item #47 (Box 177)
  - You'll Soon Get the Hang Of It (Box 177, Folder 1)
    item #47